Indiana University Assistant Vice-President for Administration records, 1973-1981 C150
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Assistant Vice-President for Administration records
1973-1981
1975-1980
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. Assistant Vice-President for Administration
C150
4.6 cubic feet 6 boxes
The office of Vice President of Administration was established during the 1974 University reorganization and was responsible for the management of a wide range of University functions. The office's diverse duties included budgetary administration, management services, computing systems, and intercollegiate athletic programs. This collection consists of records created and collected during the tenure of Herbert Glenn Ludlow, who served as Vice President of Administration from 1975-1981. The collection is organized into three series: Correspondence, Committee files, and Reports.
Access Restrictions
Select restricted records removed from folders (primarily due to containing social security numbers) and housed at the end of the collection in Box 5.
Some files are closed to researchers and are listed where they would fall intellectually but are physically located in Box 5.
Advance notice required for access.
Administrative History
The office of Vice President of Administration was established during the 1974 University reorganization and was responsible for the management of a wide range of University functions. The office's diverse duties included budgetary administration, management services, computing systems, and intercollegiate athletic programs. Incumbent Glenn Ludlow served as Assistant Vice President of Administration from 1975 until 1981. Ludlow's duties as Assistant Vice President of Administration pertained mainly to management services and included such responsibilities as management of the University registrar, faculty record systems, fellowships, safety and security, Affirmative Action Program, University scholarships and financial aid, long-range planning, internal auditing, I.U. Press, and the University Archives.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into three series: Correspondence, Committee files, and Reports.
Scope and Content Note
The Indiana University Assistant Vice-President for Administration records, 1973-1981, consists of records created and collected during the tenure of Herbert Glenn Ludlow, who served in this capacity from 1975-1981. The collection is organized into three series: Correspondence, Committee files, and Reports.
The Correspondence series includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence from Ludlow's office. It includes material dating from 1974 to 1981. He maintained both general correspondence files and separate files for the individuals with whom he communicated most often. This distinction has been maintained in the arrangement, with general files placed before the more specific author/recipient files. The general correspondence files are arranged chronologically, and the author files alphabetically. Prominent subjects and correspondents include the IU Press, David W. Kramer (University Director of Faculty Records Systems), and the university's Affirmative Action Officer, Frances Rhome.
The Committees files series consists of records on IU committees Ludlow served on in his capacity as Assistant Vice President for Administration. Series dates from 1973 to 1981, and is arranged alphabetically. Prominent committees include the Scholarship and Financial Aid Committee and the Vocational Education Committee. Files hold agendas, minutes, correspondence between members, and committee reports.
The Reports series spans the period from 1974 to 1979. It includes reports that Ludlow wrote during his tenure as Vice-President. Additionally, this series also includes materials which he assembled for reports issued by University President John Ryan. The folders in the Reports series are arranged alphabetically.
Separated Material
Floor plans (8) transferred to the Archives architectural records collection.
Papers dating outside the scope of Ludlow's tenure as VP was pulled and will be processed separately.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
2026, 2060, 2061, 2062, 2063, 2065, 2066, 2110
Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of the Registrar; Indiana University, Bloomington. Office of Student Financial Assistance; Ludlow, Herbert Glenn, 1915-1998; Indiana University -- Administration -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. Assistant Vice-President for Administration -- Archives; Indiana University. Assistant Vice-President for Administration -- Records and correspondence; Ludlow, Herbert Glenn, 1915-1998 -- Archives; Ludlow, Herbert Glenn, 1915-1998 -- Correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington -- Administration -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. Press -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. University Archives (1974-2005) -- History -- 20th century -- Sources
- Correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
    - 1981 (Box 1)
      - January-June (Box 1)
      - March-June (Box 1)
      - January-February (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
      - September-December (Box 1)
      - July-December (Box 1)
      - July-August (Box 1)
      - February-June (Box 1)
      - January-June (Box 1)
    - 1979 (Box 1)
      - August-December (Box 1)
      - July-November (Box 1)
      - May-June (Box 1)
      - March-December (Box 1)
      - March-April (Box 1)
      - January-February, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1)
      - November-December, (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - September-October (Box 1)
      - June-October (Box 1)
      - June-August (Box 1)
      - April-June (Box 1)
      - January-June (Box 1)
      - January-March (Box 1)
    - 1977 (Box 1)
      - November-December (Box 1)
      - October-December (Box 1)
      - September-October (Box 1)
      - July-September (Box 1)
      - July-August (Box 1)
      - April-June (Box 1)
      - May-June (Box 1)
      - January-April (Box 2)
      - January-March (Box 2)
    - 1976 (Box 2)
      - November-December, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - July-October, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - March-June (Box 2)
      - January-May (Box 2)
    - 1975 (Box 2)
      - September-December (Box 2)
      - June-February, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Deans and Chancellors, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Dean of the Faculties, 1976-1981 (Box 2)
    - Energy Crisis, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Indiana University Press (Box 2)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 2)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 2)
      - 1974-1978 (Box 2)
    - Information & Computer Services, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Kramer, David W. (Box 2)
      - 1978 (Box 2)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 2)
      - 1977 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 2)
      - 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Long Range Planning, Office of, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
    - Lott, John K., 1975-1976 (Box 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      (Restricted)
    - O'Neil, Robert M., 1976-1980 (Box 2)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Personnel, Office of, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
    - Rhome, Frances (Box 2)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 2)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 2)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 2)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1975 (Box 3)
    - Sample, Edson W. (Box 3)
      - 1981 (Box 3)
      - 1980 (Box 3)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - 1978 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
      - 1977 (Box 3)
        - April-June (Box 3)
        - February-March (Box 3)
      - 1976 (Box 3)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - Scherer, M.D. (Box 3)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 3)
      - 1980 (Box 3)
        - July-September (Box 3)
        - January-June (Box 3)
      - 1979 (Box 3)
        - September-December (Box 3)
        - July-August (Box 3)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - 1978 (Box 3)
      - 1977 (Box 3)
        - July-December (Box 3)
        - January-March (Box 3)
      - 1976 (Box 3)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1975 (Box 3)
    - Solt, Leo F., 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - Stevens, Jean, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - University Archives (Box 3)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 3)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - 1979 (Box 3)
        - July-October (Box 3)
        - January-April (Box 3)
      - 1978 (Box 3)
      - 1976-1978 (Box 4)
      - Wilson, George, 1977 (Box 4)
- Committee files, 1973-1981 (Box 4)
  - Academic Handbook Revision Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Addison Locke Roache Lectureship Committee (Box 4)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1977-1981 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee (AD COM), 1978 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Staff Meeting (Box 4)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Equipment Policy Review Committee, 1977-1981 (Box 4)
  - Fellowships and Grants in Aid Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Financial Aid for Part time Students, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Student Advisory Committee, 1976 (Box 4)
  - IU Northwest Academic Mission Program Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - I.U. Press Faculty Committee, 1973-1978 (Box 4)
  - IU/Stillman College Coordinating Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Information Systems Review Board (Box 4)
    - 1980 (Box 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Management Information System Steering Committee (Box 4)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Pre Award Contract Compliance Review, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Publications Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Scholarships and Financial Aids Committee (Box 4)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 4)
      - April-April (Box 4)
      - September-October (Box 4)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Search and Screen: IU Press, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Seventh District Service Academy Screening Board, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
  - Student Prospectus Committee, 1975 (Box 4)
  - TIAA/CREF Exceptions Committee (Box 4)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - Vocational Education Committee (Box 4)
    - 1974-1977 (Box 4)
    - 1976 (Box 4)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 4)
- Reports, 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Annual Conference and Reviews with VP Edgar Williams, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Duvall Cost Study, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Indiana University Faculty Research Reports, 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Interagency Taskforce on Higher Ed. Report, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Materials for August Board of Trustees Seminar, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Material for President Ryan's Presentation to Board of Trustees, 1977; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Materials for President Ryan's Statement on Federal Paperwork (Box 5)
    - 1976 (Box 5)
      - January-June (Box 5)
      - May-July (Box 6)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 6)
  - Office of the Vice President for Admin. Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Operations Review (Box 6)
    - IUPUI, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Kokomo, 1976 (Box 6)
    - South Bend, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Restricted Files (Box 6)